# Daniel A. Pinedo

# **Operations & Strategy Management**

**\** 213.999.5619

@ daniel.pinedo@cgu.edu

% pinedo.org

### **SUMMARY**

Management strategist specialized in inclusion within the global workforce, human capital strategy, and operations of machine assisted cognition and decision-making in management. Recent applied experience in creating bleeding-edge selection tools for Fortune 100 Best Company that incorporate machine-learning technology into decision-making. Strong background in research methods and statistical methods that translate and transfer into management contexts of operations and strategy. Leadership coach that elicits focus, deep listening, and relational mindfulness practice that nurtures strengths, resilience, and insights in client interactions.

# **ABILITIES**



Performance Monitoring & Evaluation



Coaching & Mentoring



Talent Research & Development



**Talent Management** 



**Nurturing Inclusive Culture** 



**Operations & Strategy** 

# **EXPERIENCE**

### Research Associate

**Accenture PLC, Talent Innovation Lab** 

## 11/2018 - Current

Member of Talent Research and Development Lab in partnership with Claremont Graduate University for consulting firm with global workforce size of 500,000+. Lab project management style was agile and iterative. Projects included:

- PROJECT 1: Literature review for statistical analysis of requirements of future job candidates in Volatile, Uncertain, Complex, and Ambiguous (VUCA) world - led to Project 2.
- PROJECT 2: Literature review and qualitative analysis of requirements from Project 1; deliverable presented to senior global management team and implementation plan initiated led to Project 3.
- PROJECT 3: Subject matter expert for creation of validated scoring measure for Project 2; consulted regional employee experience teams to synchronize initial stages of pilot with goal for global implementation IN PROGRESS

### **External Consultant**

#### **ICM Partners**

Part of a course-based project for one of the largest creative talent agencies in the world. HR department is in the process of restructuring with recent hiring of CHRO.

- 150 + employees participated in organizational diagnosis of assistant agent job design and agent leadership development that provided insights into specific discrepancies in how agents and assistants give and receive job feedback.
- 1-year development plan presented to CHRO with training cost savings projected to be \$10-\$15,000 per new assistant in year one.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Lecturer

#### **Mount Saint Mary's University**

**1** 01/2016 - 05/2018

% msmu.edu

Undergraduate contract faculty position in psychology department. This role included teaching courses in Research Methods, Social Psychology, and Organizational Psychology; academic counseling, and administration.

- Managed increase in participation in undergraduate research colloquium of students by over 300% and outside attendees by over 1000%.
- Academic counseling for 15 students on an ongoing basis that included tracking graduation requirements, course selection, career
  counseling, monitoring degree progress, and crisis counseling with 100% graduation rate of those students.

### Clinical Psychologist Intern

#### **Sovereign Health Group**

**1** 08/2014 - 08/2015

Inpatient facility with individual and group therapy, psychological assessment, and internal consulting services.

Assisted program director in streamlining management of distribution of caseload to employees, leading to 25% increase in overall
revenue by increasing cases per employee, and increasing insurance billing overall.

### Manager / Interim Director

### **Sofia University Electroencephalography Lab**

**1** 09/2012 - 06/2013

% sofia.edu

Academic EEG lab specialized in analysis of meditative states

- created training program for graduate students with four paid positions for training in using EEG equipment and running experiments with human subjects.
- Researched potential grant funding totally \$500,000, and reported updates of grant-writing weekly to the office of the provost.

## **Teaching Assistant**

### Institute of Transpersonal Psychology (Sofia University)

**1** 09/2011 - 12/2012

% sofia.edu

Teaching assistant to Dr. Arthur Hastings, faculty of research methods for PhD psychology program.

 Graded papers, co-taught, and provided office hours for assistance to doctoral students in Doctoral Research Seminar (FA11-12), and Doctoral Thesis Seminar (SP12)

# **Network Operations Engineer**

### **Oversee**

**10/2007 - 08/2008** 

% oversee.net

Network operations for website portfolio company. Role was mission critical as network infrastructure was primary revenue generation avenue of company.

- Responsible for entire revenue-generating network infrastructure of \$100 million company, with 100% compliance of service level
  agreements for all internal clients within company.
- Oversaw 2 catastrophic network outages due to developer deployment errors and ensured mitigation of downtime to under 10
  minutes in both cases, including physical access to co-located network infrastructure
- Debriefed CTO in each outage case.

# **EDUCATION**

# MA Organizational Behavior & Evaluation

### **Claremont Graduate University**

• Emphasis in Business Administration

# MA Clinical Psychology

### **Sofia University**

### BA

### **Naropa University**

# **STRENGTHS**



# Strategic

Knowing and implementing multiple solutions in real-time



### Individualization

Finding and matching the strengths of others



### Relator

Facilitating excellence



### Learner

Improving current and gaining new skills



### Ideation

Connecting with concepts and people

# **TECHNOLOGIES**

# **Programming**

R SPSS C++ Python LaTeX

### **Statistics**

ANOVA Multiple Regression Social Network Analysis Psychometric Network Analysis

Categorical Data Analysis Non-Parametric Data Analysis